-=THE LAST FANTASY=- 本片内容以及字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=THE LAST FANTASY=- 本片內容以及字幕僅供學習交流 嚴禁用於商業途徑
This door?
是這間嗎？
This box or that box?
這個箱子還是那個啊？
Are they all for me?
這些都是給我的？
Cool. Thanks!
酷啊，謝謝
Hey, where are you going? Hey, what are you doing?
嘿，你去哪兒了？ 嘿，你要幹什麼？
Hey, open the door Hey! What's going on?
嘿，把門開開！ 嘿！怎麼回事？
There is nothing, no name, no face
那兒什麼都沒有，沒有名字，沒有外貌
I was born into nothingness,
我被降臨到虛無的世界
you could say I don't exist.
可以說，我從不存在
Daddy, look what I can do!
爸，快瞧我現在做的！
Very Good!
非常好！
Hi!
嘿！
Hallo!
你好！
Could you help me? I lost my goggles
能幫我一下嗎？我的游泳鏡掉了
Dad, look.
爸，快看
Great.
很好
They are down there in the deep wateg but I can't dive that deep.
它掉深水區了，我潛不到那麼深
Dad, you are not looking.
爸，你根本都沒看
Of course I am.
噢，知道了
- Would you help me?  - Yeah sure.
- 能幫我嗎？    - 好的，可以
Lotte, wait here in the shallow wateg I'll be right back.
洛特，在這淺水區等著，我馬上就回來
So, where are your goggles?
大概掉在哪兒？
Down there.
這下面
There you go.
給
Thanks!
謝謝！
No problem!
沒關係！
Would you go on the slide with me. I get scared on my own.
跟我一起去滑梯吧，我一個人不敢滑
No way.
不行
Or we could play 'animal jumping',
或者我們去玩「動物跳水」
I'll jump into the water and pretend to be an animal and you have to guess what I am.
我學一種動物姿勢跳水，你來猜是什麼動物
I am here with my daughter.
我是帶女兒來的
Your daughter sucks at doing the handstand.
你女兒玩的那個水中倒立姿勢不對
She can't do it at all!
她做那麼差勁
What are you talking about?
你在胡說些什麼？
What the..., Hey, stop this bullshit! Leave my daughter alone!
嘿！別做這樣的傻事了！別來煩我的女兒！
Lotte, come on... let's get something to drink.
洛特，我們去喝點東西吧
Asshole!
混蛋
Mrs. Heine?
海納女士？
I am one of Nicolas's friends. We play soccer together
我是尼庫拉斯的朋友，我們一起踢球的
Nicolas isn't home.
尼庫拉斯他不在
I know... but I borrowed him my knee guards,
我知道…可我把自己的護腿板借給他了
and just wanted to ask, if I could get them back.
然後我想問問能不能拿回來
I need them for tomorrow's game. Otherwise, I won't be allowed to play.
我明天比賽要用的，要不然就不能上場了
Come in,
進來吧
but please take off your shoes.
請把鞋脫了
I have an appointment with detective Becker or Egger.
我要找貝克爾探長或者叫艾格爾？
Decker chief superintendent Decker.
戴克爾，總警司戴克爾
You are standing on my foot.
您踩著我的腳了
Oh, I am sorry.
額，對不起
Give me your umbrella!
把您的傘給我吧！
And get me some rubber boots.
再去幫我找一雙膠鞋來
Do you have any idea of when Nicolas will be back?
您覺得尼庫拉斯什麼時候會回來？
Our team would collect some money,in order to help out.
要是有必要的話，我們球隊可以捐點錢的
That's very kind, but I'am afraid ransom won't help.
謝謝好意，不過我覺得錢起不到作用
The knee guards,they must be in the cupboard, somewhere.
護腿板應該是在櫃子裏面
I didn't know that Nicolas is still playing with dolls.
我之前還不知道尼庫拉斯還在玩毛絨娃娃
Not Friedolin, the rabbit, please don't touch him!
別碰福利多林，這兔娃娃
Hello, I'm Friedolin. I am cold and I am all alone.
你好，我是福利多林 我好冷，而且一直一個人
Put him back! Put him back!
把它放回去！把它放回去！
Do you know, who I am?
知道我是誰嗎？
I think, it's time for you to leave.
我覺得你該走了！
Mrs. Meinert?
麥納特女士？
Decker, we talked on the phone.
戴克爾，阿歷克山大·戴克爾 我們之前通過電話
Or shoud I say doctor Meinert.
我是不是該叫你麥納特博士？
Meinert is fine.
叫我麥納特就行
Thank's for coming down so quickly.
很感謝能如此迅速趕來
I think we can save the compliments.
我覺得我們可以跳過這些恭維之詞了
If I understood correctly, we are pushed for time.
要是我理解得沒錯的話，目前我們應該爭分奪秒
Who was that?
剛才是誰？
Nobody.
沒啥
The boy was last seen when leaving school after his sixth lesson.
這男孩最後一次被目擊是在他上完第六節課後放學回家
He never arrived at home. We are still searching his way to school.
然後卻再沒出現，我們仍舊在他家與學校沿路搜查
Do you know what mouldy sandwiches, like them ones mean?
您知道這些發霉的三明治意味著什麼嗎？
This syndrome is almost exclusively found in boys.
這種情況一般只在男孩子身上出現
They don't want to eat their sandwich, but they are unable to throw it away.
他們不願意吃給他們準備的三明治 但又不知道要把這東西從書包裏扔掉
So the sandwiches start moulding... just like a bad conscience.
所以這些三明治就會在書包裏發霉，變質… 就好像壞情緒一樣
Do you have kids, Mrs Meinert?
您有孩子嗎，麥納特女士？
I don't get along with kids.
我跟孩子處不好
Good afternoon ladies and gentleman, may I see you tickets please?
下午好，女士們先生們，請大家出示一下車票
Are you also travelling without a ticket?
你也是逃票嗎？
May I?
讓我一下？
I don't mind if you need to piss, unless you need to go for a shit,
你如果要小便，我不介意的，除非你想要上大號
that would be pretty uncool.
那就太掃興了
Did that hurt?
穿這耳洞疼嗎？
Are you pretending to be on an 'emo trip'? Because I am talking too much, or what?
不想搭理我還是咋的？
You look propper gay. But you have nice eyes.
你看起來更像是同性戀 不過眼睛很漂亮
I need to get out of here.
我得出去了
Cute.
可愛
Pussy.
娘炮
What are you doing there?
你躺這兒幹嘛？
Oh, I am sorry... I was just thinking.
哦，我正在想…… 很抱歉…
Don't worry I'll take care of that!
沒事，我來弄這些！
Maybe you could help me. I am looking for something personal from your son.
或許您能幫我一下，我想找一些您孩子的私人物品
Something that was important to him.
一些對於他來說很重要的物件
The football.
那個足球
Do you have something more personal.
有沒有更私密一點的
It's signed by all players.
這上面有全隊球員簽名的
What about this rabbit?
這隻兔娃娃怎樣？
Lost
不見了
Please take off your shoes inside the house
下次進屋前請脫鞋
Mum?
媽？
Mum!
媽！
Get up! Come on, get up!
來！快點，起來！
Mathilda, why aren't you at school?
馬蒂爾達，你怎麼沒去上學？
It's half past seven.
都已經六點半了
Did you smoke?
你抽煙了？
Come on, get up.
快，起來吧！
It's all right mum.
沒事的，媽
I don't want to.
我不想洗
But I don't want to.
我真不想啊
But you have to.
你必須得洗
The water is cold.
這水太涼了
Look, I made it warmer
瞧，我把它調熱了
But it's still cold.
可還是很涼
I made some Spaghetti for you, you like eating them, don't you?
我給你做了意大利麵條 你喜歡吃的，是不是啊？
I saw it, thanks.
我看到了，謝謝
I am sick.
我好難受
Mama you have to take a shower
媽媽，你得沖一下
The water is cold.
水太涼了
But I just made it warmer.
但我剛已經調熱了呢
But it's still cold.
但還是很涼
Mum, you smell of piss.
媽，你身上一股尿騷味
How are you talking to me?!
你怎麼說話呢！
You shouldn't talk in this way with your mother.
你不該跟你媽媽這個樣子說話的
I am your mum.
我畢竟是你媽
I am sorry.
對不起
The water is cold.
水是涼的
I made it warmer
我已經又調熱了
AUAAAAA. IT'S BOILING!
啊…好冷！
How was school?
學校裏還好嗎？
Your mother asked you something.
你媽在問你話呢
Would you please turn of the TV At least, as long as we're having dinner.
能把電視關上嗎？至少別在吃飯時候看
TV: Somewhere out there, there is someone who knows where our son is.
肯定有人知道我們的兒子在哪裏
We beg you, don't hurt our child.
我們求你了，別傷害孩子
Did you hear what your mother said?
沒聽見你媽剛才說的嗎？
We do whatever you want, but please give us a sign of life.
我們可以答應你的任何要求 但請告知我們他的音訊
Show us that our son is all right.
讓我們知道我們的兒子現在沒事
Nicolas is a good boy...
尼庫拉斯是一個好孩子…
he loves playing football and he is very popular with his friends.
他喜歡踢足球，在朋友圈裏很受歡迎
Nicolas loves his rabbits and cares about them attentively.
尼庫拉斯喜歡他的寵物兔… 把它們照料得非常好
I am sorry, I can't do this.
我無法繼續，抱歉
Hello?
你好？
Hello. Is anybody there?
喂，是不是有人？
Don't go away. Hey!
別走…嘿！
Mrs. Meinert?
麥納特女士？
I have a message for you.
這是給您的
Please give a call! Max
[請給我電話！  - 馬克斯]
If this gentleman calls again, tell him that I've left.
要是這位先生來電，就告訴他我出門了
Thank you!
謝謝
Yes?
喂？
Hello Mrs Meinert, it's me. We have a sign of life.
麥納特女士，是我 我們得到孩子的訊息了
The mating dance of the humpback wales can last for many hours
座頭鯨的交配舞蹈可以持續好幾個小時
and is often accompanied by complex signing.
而且經常發出複雜的聲音
In order to mate, the wales swim tightly along side one another
為了交配，鯨魚會緊貼著另一頭一起游泳
mainly upright, while their bellies are touching and they nibble
幾乎完全筆直，然後它們的腹部會相互觸碰
on each others mouth.
而它們還會輕咬對方的嘴巴
Mathilda, would you come to the front please?
瑪蒂爾達，請到講台上來
Mathilda!
瑪蒂爾達！
Please explain, how mammal fertilisation works.
請解釋一下哺乳動物是如何受精的
And take your hair out of your mouth, please!
請不要咬你的頭髮了
Where does the fertilisation take place?
受精是在哪裏發生的？
In the cunt.
在屄裏
We found the video on many of our student's mobiles.
在我校許多學生的手機裏發現了這段視頻
It's like approaching dogs. Just don't show them that you are scared.
就好似在跟狗狗接觸，別讓他們感覺到你在害怕
That's my seat.
這是我的位置
Hi!
嗨！
Hello!
哈嘍！！
Thank you.
謝謝
First of all, I am asking you all to turn off your mobile phones.
首先，我想要求大家先把手機都關掉
If I hear one of them ring, I am going to collect them all.
如果聽到一聲鈴響，我就會沒收你們所有的手機
Well, this is Mrs. Meinert from the police.
這位是警局來的麥納特女士
She would like to ask you a few questions.
她將會問大家幾個問題
Which one of you has seen the video of Nicolas.
你們中有誰看過了尼庫拉斯的那段視頻
Louder!
大點聲！
Which one of you has seen the video of Nicolas, the boy in the cellar
你們中有誰看過了尼庫拉斯的那段視頻？ 那個被關在地下室的男生
No one will get into trouble if they have seen it. I watched it myself.
沒人會因為看過那段視頻而惹上麻煩的，我也看了
I watched it. A friend sent it to me.
我看了，一個朋友發給我看的
And what did you think, when you saw it?
當你看到它的時候，你是怎麼想的？
The bunny was cute.
兔娃娃很可愛
I, I also watched the video, I thought it was horrorifying.
我…我也看了，我覺得太陰暗恐怖了
I thought, it was funny.
我認為比較有意思
That is not funny.
怎麼能覺得這個有意思呢？
It clapped when he fell.
誰要是喜歡就鼓掌唄
I want to see the victim.
我想要見他
Who else has seen the video?
還有誰看過這視頻？
Is it real?
是真的嗎？
Yes, the video is real.
沒錯，是真實的
We are going to have one-on-one interviews with all of you now.
我將會跟你們每個人單獨談話 請給你們父母電話…
Please let your parents know that you are going to be late.
告訴他們你們今天會晚點放學
I want to see the victim, and I want an ice-cream.
我要見那個受害者，而且還要個冰淇淋
Mrs. Schockenhoff. Mrs. SCHOCKENHOOOFFFF!!!
舒肯霍夫女士，舒肯霍夫女士！
Yes, please.
什麼事？
Wait for me after school.
放學後等我
I need to pee.
我想要上廁所
Name and grade, please!
告訴我姓名還有年級
Nine B.
九年級B班
Name?
名字呢？
I don't have a name.
我沒有名字
Everybody has a name.
每個人都有名字
Not me.
可我沒
Don't you like your name?
你不喜歡自己的名字嗎？
Your name is Claudia Meinert, right.
你的名字是克勞迪婭·麥納特，對不？
Yea.
對
Do you have a second name?
你有小名嗎？
Hanne, Hannelore. And you?
漢娜，漢娜羅拉，你呢？
Did your father used to call you like that? Hanne?
你的爸爸會那麼叫你嗎？漢娜？
Why don't you just pick a name, one that you like?
你為何不選一個你自己喜歡的名字呢？
You don't choose names, names are given to you.
名字不是自己選的，是別人給的！
Parents give their children names.
父母會給他們的孩子起名字
It says here, your name is
這上面寫了你的名字叫…
I don't have a name.
我沒名字
Well, did you know the boy from the video?
好吧，你認識視頻裏的那個男生嗎？
We play in the same club.
我們在同一家俱樂部踢球
And did you ever fight with him.
那你有沒有跟他打過架
He is very popular
他很招人喜歡的
I asked you,if you ever had a fight with him.
我問你的是，你有沒有跟他打過架
Do you know anybody who has had a fight with him.
或者你知不知道有誰跟他打過架
Like I said, he is very popular.
就像我說的，他很招人喜歡
Maybe a bit too popular
或許是因為太招人喜歡了呢
It's says here that you are highly talented, you skipped the seventh grade.
上面說你智商很高，直接把七年級跳過了
It's not easy?
挺不容易吧？
What?
什麼？
Making friends.
交朋友
I have other interests.
我有別的興趣
For example?
比如？
Girls, fashion, music. May I go now?
女孩，時尚，音樂！我能走了嗎？
And where exactly is your victim supposed to be?
那個受害者人呢？
Hey, what is this shit?
嘿，這算是哪一出？
Switch the lights back on!
快把燈打開！
Hello?
喂？
I am here.
我在這兒
Switch the lights on immediately!
快點開燈啊！
I am right behind you.
我就在你身後
Is the victim in here too?
受害者也在這兒？
Yes.
是的
When are you going to make it happen?
你打算什麼時候做？
Kill the victim?
什麼時候殺他？
I have a special plan with him beforehand.
我接下來還有一個特別計劃
What's that?
什麼計劃？
He is going to be my birthday present.
我將會是我的生日禮物
I want to watch, when you do it.
你殺他的時候，我想看
I want to be there, when you do it.
你殺他的時候，我要在場
I want to watch, when somebody is dying.
我想看著人死去的樣子
Mrs. Schweizer?
施瓦茨女士？
My name is Claudia Meinert.
我的名字是克勞迪婭·麥納特
Did something happen to my husband?
我丈夫出什麼狀況了？
Your husband is fine.
您的丈夫沒事
I have a few questions regarding your son.
我想問幾個關於您兒子的問題
I imagined him to be much taller.
我的想像中，他個子更高點
Come over here!
來這邊！
What's the matter?
怎麼啦？
You wanted to see him. Now you saw him.
你想看他，現在你已經看到了
I thought we were going do something together today.
我以為我們倆今天會一起做點什麼的呢
Also, I still want my ice cream.
而且我還沒吃到冰淇淋呢
You will get your ice cream.
會給你吃的
Asshole.
混蛋
Give me your watch!
把你的手錶給我！
I asked you to give me your watch!
讓你把表給我！你的表！
YOUR WATCH!!!
給我你的手錶！
May try yours?
能嘗一下你的嗎？
Tomorrow is fun fair I want you to take me there.
明天有遊樂園，我想讓你帶我去
No time.
沒工夫
Else, I will tell everybody where your victim is.
那我就告訴所有人
If you do that?
要是你敢那麼做…
What then?
那就怎樣？
Then you'll never see someone dying.
那你就永遠看不到人是怎麼死的
I bet, you don't dare to do it anyway.
反正我賭你沒膽那麼做
Tomorrow at five at the crawler.
明天五點鐘在旋轉飛爪前面
Is that a date.
算是約會嗎？
Cool.
爽
See you tomorrow.
明天見
Come on you have to eat something.
來吃點東西吧
I am not hungry.
我不餓
Shall I make you a salad.
要不給你去拌個色拉？
I don't understand how you can eat at all.
真不明白你竟然還能吃得進
Are you Nicolas Dad?
你是尼庫拉斯的爸爸嗎？
I promised Nicolas to feed his rabbits while he is away.
我答應尼庫拉斯，在他不在家的時候幫他喂兔子的
Moritz, Finny, Schnuffy and Carl.
莫裏茨，芬妮，史努飛還有卡爾
When did you talk to Nicolas?
你什麼時候跟尼庫拉斯談的？
May I come in?
我能進屋嗎？
Sure, come in.
當然，請進
Weren't you here yesterday?
你昨天已經來過的吧？
What do you want?
你想幹什麼？
He claims that he spoke to Nicolas.
他說他跟尼庫拉斯聊過
Oh, did I interrupt your dinner? Should I come back later?
是不是打攪到你們吃晚飯了？ 那我過會兒再來吧？
When exactly did you talk to Nicolas?
你究竟是什麼時候跟尼庫拉斯說話的？
May I have something to drink?
可以給我點喝的嗎？
Milk, if you have any.
有沒有牛奶？
That is Nicolas seat.
那是尼庫拉斯的位置
Please explain us in detail, when exactly you spoke to Nicolas.
請確切告訴我們，你是什麼時候跟尼庫拉斯談話的
Would you make me a sandwich?
再給我切塊麵包吧？
Out! OUT!
出去！出去！
Anja, wait! Wait!
安雅，等等！等等！
Oh, I am sorry.
額，非常抱歉
It's late, my parents are waiting for me with dinner.
已經不早了，我爸媽還在等我吃飯呢
Where did you get this watch?
這手錶是哪裏來的？
I want her to make me a sandwiche, with salami.
她應該給我準備麵包的，要帶火腿片的
And now, you are going to tell me where you got this damn watch from!
告訴我，你是從哪裏得到這塊手錶的！
I want her to make it!
我是讓她給我！
I know it's late, but...
我知道現在不早了，不過…
My wife is already asleep. Maybe it's better you come back tomorrow.
我愛人已經睡了，你最好明天再來
I just wanted to ask if you know this boy.
我只是想問問你們是不是認識這個男生
No!
不！
Five minutes. Give me five minutes.
五分鐘！ 就只要給我五分鐘！
After that, you can do anything you want with me.
五分鐘之後，你讓我做什麼都行
He said, he knows where Nicolas is. He's got his watch.
他說他知道尼庫拉斯在什麼地方，他有孩子的手錶
Open this door immediately. Open the doog right now! RIGHT NOW!
把門打開！立刻把門打開！馬上！
Morning.
早安
I have a new boyfriend.
我交了新男友
Didn 't you want to buy milk?
你沒有買牛奶回來嗎？
I think, I am in love.
我想我是愛上他了
We want to go to the fair tonight. Do you have any money?
我們今晚要去遊樂園，你有錢嗎？
You know how it works?
你知道應該怎麼用的吧？
I would be a shit grandma, you know that.
我可不想現在就當外婆，你知道的
Thank you.
謝謝
I am expecting company tonight, would be cool, if you could stay in your room.
我今晚還有訪客，最好你就待在自己的房間
Yeah!
好！
I am a child, I am incapable of crime, whatever I do.
我還是小孩，無法指控我的，不管我幹了什麼
I know the law.
我懂法
So, I can go now?
我現在可以走了嗎？
This says, your birthday is in three days.
上面說，你三天後就要過生日了
You will turn fourteen and that means you will no longer be freed of crime.
那時候你就十四歲了，也就意味著不會被免予指控
In three days, Nicolas is dead.
三天之後，尼庫拉斯就死了
I am tired, may I go now?
我累了，可以先走嗎？
We can't do anything, he knows that.
他知道我們做不了什麼
We will claim charge against the father.
我們會起訴他父親
Bring the boy home! Clarify if the parents comply their fiduciary duty.
帶這孩子回家！向他們父母闡明監護義務
We will be observing him, day and night.
我們會日夜監控他的
What the fuck.
他在幹啥！
Our Hanne is pregnant.
我們的漢娜懷孕了
Give it back!
還給我！
Did you already know, our Hanne is pregnant?
你知道嗎，這位漢娜懷孕了
That's enough!
鬧夠了！走吧
Do you already have name for the little one?
給小寶寶起好名字了沒？
Or is it going to be a little girl, a little Hanne?
或者是個小女孩呢……一個小漢娜？
Will you ride the crawler with me?
帶我一起坐旋轉飛爪吧？
Just one time... I get scared on my own.
就一次…我一個人不敢坐
I am here with my children.
我是帶我孩子一起來的
Otherwise, I am going to tell my mother that you touched me.
不然我就告訴我媽你摸我
I did what?
我啥？
You touched my tits.
你摸了我的胸
Are you nuts?
你神經病啊？
Just one round. One little bitty round.
就坐一輪，就那麼一小會兒
Get off!
一邊去！
Asshole.
混蛋
Sabine Meissner Seventy, four years of age, she fell in her apartment,
薩比娜·麥斯納，七十四歲，摔倒在自己的公寓
three weeks later the neighbours complained about the smell.
三周之後，鄰居抱怨她屋子有異味傳出
Blistering on the lips, mucosal skin dried out and lacerated,
嘴唇起泡，粘膜層乾裂
the tonsils inflamed.
扁桃體發炎
That's how somebody looks, who died of thirst.
那些被渴死的人看上去就是這副樣子
I know it from the TV
我在電視上見過
Well then, touch hen
那行，你摸摸看
It's just a dead body.
屍體而已
Feels like a cold apple, and now?
感覺像是冰過的蘋果，現在呢？
If Nicolas dies, he will feel the same.
要是尼庫拉斯死了，摸起來的感覺也是一樣
And you will feel guilty for your entire life, because you were unable to save him.
然後你的餘生都將會因為沒能救出他而自責
His grades are good, we have no problems with him.
他學習成績很好，我們跟他也沒什麼問題
He is one of the best students in his year, at least in written work.
他是他們班上最好的學生之一，至少從考試成績來看
I think, you didn't really get my point. Your son committed a serious crime.
我不知道你們有沒有領會我的意思 你們的兒子現在涉及刑事犯罪
Are you sure, I mean do you have any evidence?
您確定嗎？我是說，您有證據嗎？
He confessed.
他親口承認了
Do you mind if I smoke?
不介意我抽煙吧？
Not in the house, Cora please!
請別在屋裏抽煙，科拉！
Has your son changed at all recently?
你們有沒有感覺到孩子近段時間有什麼變化？
How were we supposed to? He barely even speaks to us.
怎麼感覺？他幾乎不跟我們交流
That's a change, don't you think?
這就是一種變化，你不覺得嗎？
We thought, it's the age.
我們還以為，青春期都這樣
Your son no longer answers to his name. I think that's not normal, don't you?
你們的孩子已經不願意提及他的名字了 我覺得這有點不尋常，是不是？
Sammy, would you please hand me my coat?
薩米，能幫我把外套拿來嗎？
I am sorry,could you please repeat your question?
不好意思，您能再重複一下剛才的問題嗎？
If your son doesn't answer to his own name, to what does he answer then?
要是您兒子不理睬自己的名字，那他會應什麼？
Nothing. Just: Hey you.
沒什麼，就是：喂，你！
Do you remember any triggeg a fight maybe?
有什麼矛盾起因嗎？
He just stopped talking to us.
他就是那樣停止跟我們交流了
It got worse last year
去年開始更糟糕了
He used to work things out by himself.
他總是自己解決自己的問題
As I said, it got worse last year.
就像我說的，去年開始變糟糕的
I can't force my child to talk to me.
我肯定也無法強迫孩子跟我交流
But you try it over and over again.
但你一直在不斷地說
Yes, unlike you, I try to talk to my son, that's right.
沒錯，反正不像你，我試圖跟我兒子交流，那很正常
Do you still have physical contact with your son?
你們還有沒有肢體語言上的交流？
Touching, hugs, cuddles...
安撫，擁抱，接近…
He is thirteen. I don't get your question.
他已經十三歲了，我不明白您的意思
If I understand you right,
要是我理解的沒錯的話
your son has been socially completely isolated for more than one year now.
您孩子已經至少有一年時間，從他的社會關係中脫離了
That's right you could say that.
沒錯，可以那麼說
No, that's not right. Only recently he completed an internship
不，不是那樣的，最近他還去做了實習呢
a student internship in the youth well-fare office.
在青年福利局的學生實習
That's kind of social, isn't it.
那算是一種社交活動吧？
Does that mean it's all my fault?
難道現在都覺得是我的責任？
This isn't about fault.
現在不是誰的責任的問題
What then?
那要咋樣？
I think, you are hiding something from me.
我感覺您有在隱瞞什麼
Nicolas?
尼庫拉斯？
What do you want from me?
你想要我做什麼？
Will this be one of this: Show me your room and I will tell you who you are thing?
現在你要說的是不是： 帶我去看你的房間，然後我告訴你是誰
My self perception is disturbed.
你打攪到我自慰了
Would you please wait outside?
你能不能去外面等著？
Nietzsche said: We do not accuse nature of being immoral if it sends us a thunderstorm.
尼采曾說過，即使大自然帶給我們暴風雨 我們也不會去指責它的不道德
Why do we call a human being immoral if he kills. No one is born evil.
要是有人殺了人，為何我們稱之為邪惡？ 沒有人天生是邪惡的
So, it's society's fault or that of the parents?
那是社會的錯，還是父母的錯？
May I have one too?
能給我也來一支嗎？
Nice lighten
打火機不錯
I had it since I was twelve, pure brass, you won't find this anymore today.
我十二歲的時候就得到它了，純銅打造 現如今是找不到這樣的貨了
May I?
給我看看？
You're welcome!
給！
Did your father give it to you?
是你父親送給你的？
No, I just found in somewhere, and never lost it since.
不是，是我自己弄來的，然後就沒丟棄過
Look at the lighter!
瞧這個打火機
I just want to answer your question.
我只想回答你的問題
Until now, I am nobody, just someone that you have barely known for three days.
直到現在，我對於你來說 只不過是一個剛認識了三天的泛泛之輩
Look at the lighter!
你該看著這打火機的！
Now I am the one who broke your lighten
現在我則成為了弄壞你打火機的人
That has been my favourite lighter for over forty years.
這是我最喜歡的打火機，跟了我四十年
The more it hurts you, the deeper our relationship.
傷得你越深，我們之間的關係也越深
You want to have a relationship with me, and therefore you brake my lighter?
你想跟我建立關係，所以就弄壞了我的打火機？
If this is the only way to get in contact with you.
要是這是能跟你獲得接觸的唯一途徑
Now you will never forget me.
現在你永遠都不會忘記我了
No, this I'll never forget.
不，我永遠不會忘記你的惡行
And that is his motive, he want's a relationship with her at any cost.
這就是他的動機 他想不惜一切代價跟她建立起關係
If you would be a guy, I would smack you for that.
要是我再年輕幾歲，我會因此而揍你的
I will buy you a new one.
我會給你再弄個新的來
I also know a Nietzsche saying...
我也知道尼采的一句話
The one who fights with monsters needs to be careful
跟惡魔戰鬥的時候，需要注意…
that he doesn't turn into a monster himself.
…不要讓自己變成惡魔
Like I said, I'll get you an new one.
我說了，會給你弄個新的
May I ask you a personal question?
能問你一個私人問題嗎？
Maybe another time.
還是下次吧
Fucking cold today.
今天真他媽冷啊
Coffee would be good.
有杯咖啡喝就好了
I'll go and check what's going on.
我去看看怎麼回事
Nicolas.
尼庫拉斯
Oh shit.
見鬼
Come I'll clean you.
來，我給你弄乾淨
You know, that happened to me once, too
知道嗎，我也曾這樣過
I woke up becausel had to pee so badly.
我被驚醒了，發現尿濕了一大片
And then?
然後呢？
I pissed the whole bed.
我幾乎把整張床都尿透了
The next day it stank like.
第二天，它聞起來…
Like a pissed tramp.
像一個臭流浪漢
Right, like a fully pissed tramp.
沒錯，像一個滿身尿騷的流浪漢
Come, we'll get you fresh clothes.
來，我給你弄乾淨的衣服來
Advertisement for telephone sex.
[色情電話的廣告]
Our people are on it. For now we can only wait.
我們的人在裏面盯著，我們也只能等待
Anything new about the cellar?
有關於那地下室的線索嗎？
A cellar without any windows, every second cellar in town looks like this.
沒有窗戶的地下室，這城市有半數的地下室都這模樣
Anything wrong?
怎麼啦？
No.
沒事
You looked at me strangely.
你看我的眼神好奇怪
I didn't look at you.
我沒在看你
Sure, you looked at me strangely.
就有，你就是在奇怪地看著我
Here, some new games this is even adult rated.
給你幾個新遊戲，這個剛出的，甚至還有限制級的
I want to go home.
我想要回家
You can go home again, when your mother does what I say.
要是你的媽媽按我說的做，你就能回家了
Where were you?  We had a date?
你去哪了？ 我們約好了的
No time.
沒工夫
But for the victim you have time, or what?
但你卻有時間去找那受害者玩，是不是？
His name is Nicolas.
他叫尼庫拉斯
You are bleeding.
你受傷了
You are crazy, you know that?
你是神經病，知道嗎？
Like I said, we are a perfect match.
所以我說咱們倆是天生一對
Can I crash at your place tonight?
我今晚能去你那睡嗎？
No time.
沒工夫
Isn't that the cop chick from school?
那個不是來過學校的女警察嗎？
Do you want to go swimming?
有興趣去游泳嗎？
Yes.
好呀
Will you slide with me, I am scared alone.
跟我一起滑吧，我一個人害怕
Faster! Come on, faster!
快呀，快點！
I want an ice-cream.
我要吃冰淇淋
We have to talk.
我們得談談
Thanks.
謝謝
Anja.
安雅
Thanks.
謝啦
Can you put some lotion on my back?
能給我的背上擦點油嗎？
Also under the bikini!
從比基尼下面擦！
Mathilda, what do want to have for dinner?
- 你晚上想要吃什麼？ - 無所謂
What's your favourite dish?
你最愛吃什麼？
Spaghetti Bolognese. But real Bolognese, not the canned stuff.
番茄牛肉醬意面 不過要真正的牛肉醬，而不是罐頭貨
Can you make that?
你會做嗎？
Yes.
恩
HELLO! HELP! HELP!
有人嗎！救命！救命！
HELLO! Is there anybody out there?
喂！外面有人嗎？
That's really yummy. Are you not hungry?
真的很好吃，你不餓嗎？
We eat all together!
我們大家一起吃！
I am not hungry.
我不餓
I want you to eat.
我想讓你吃
You still have to ask how school was.
你還得問我們在學校裏過得怎麼樣
How was school?
在學校裏怎麼樣？
Good.
很好
We are eating!
我們吃飯！
These are the best Spaghetti ever May I have some more?
這是我吃過的最好吃的意面 我能再吃一點嗎？
What is this about?
這又算是哪一出？
I am hungry
我餓了
But you are not invited.
可又沒有邀請你
Either I get some of your Spaghetti...
要麼讓我吃點你的意大利面…
or I will tell the others what yummy meal you have here.
要麼我去告訴別人這兒屋子裏面有好吃的
Which others?
什麼別人？
Would you hand me the sauce, please?
幫我把肉醬遞一下吧？
I talked to you parents. They want you to come home after dinner.
我跟你父母說過了 他們想讓你晚飯之後就回家
I stay here for the night.
我晚上還想要在這兒
We stay here for the night. There are pigs outside everywhere.
我們在這兒過夜，外面到處是警察
You are under age, that's the law.
你還未成年，法律就這麼規定的
Unless we all stay here for the night.
除非我們大家都留在這兒
The sauce. Please!
我要肉醬！
Mathilda Herwick, mother on welfare, single parent, alcohol.
瑪蒂爾達·海爾維克，母親在領救濟，單身，酗酒
Father?
父親呢？
Died, car accident, when the kid was three.
死了，車禍，那時孩子三歲
Did he say what he wants?
他有說過想要什麼嗎？
The deal is: The police retreats in return I will stay in the house.
跟他說好的是，警察全部撤走，我單獨留在這兒
That's a shit deal.
這算是什麼狗屁
He is going to bring it to an end as long as he is incapable of crime.
在他失去未成年豁免權之前 肯定會對事情做一個了結的
Nicolas has twenty eight hours left.
所以尼庫拉斯還有二十八小時
That's a beautiful pattern.
這個碗的造型真不錯
Japanese cherry blossom, the wedding gift of my parents, in law.
日本櫻花，這是我公公婆婆給的結婚禮物
Where shall I put it?
該把它放哪裏？
There inside the cupboard.
放那邊櫃子
How long for have you known your husband?
你認識你的丈夫有多久了？
We married when I was pregnant with Nicolas.
我們是在我懷了尼庫拉斯之後結的婚
And before Raphael,was there any one else in your life.
除了拉斐爾，你之前有過其他男人嗎？
I want to feed the rabbits, they are hungry too.
我要喂兔子，它們也餓了
There.
那兒
You didn't answer my question.
你還沒回答我的問題呢
I guess, that's none of your business.
我覺得那不關你的事
There is a mistake. Fiftysix divided by eight is seven not six.
這兒做錯了，56除以8等於7，而不是6
No, the eight isn't wrong, the six is.
不是，這個八沒錯，而是六錯了
Fortyeight divided by eight is six. Two times six is?
48除以8等於6，6乘以2等於？
Six.
六
Six times two is twelve.
六乘以二等於十二
Three times four is?
三乘以四等於？
Three times four
三乘以四，三乘以四等於？
Six.
六
Six times two is twelve. Three times four is?
六乘以二等於十二，三乘以四等於？
Not six, twelve!
不是六，是十二！
Six, six, six
六，六，六，…
sex
性
Twelve, six times two is twelve.
十二，六乘以二等於十二
Six, point six six six.
六，六點六六六…
Sex.
性
Shall we play something?
我們來玩點什麼吧？
When I was a kid I had a rabbit too, his name was Franz.
在我小的時候，也有一隻兔子，名叫弗蘭茲
A birthday present from may father
是我父親送我的生日禮物
Franz grew and grew, grew and grew, only at Christmas Franz got very small again.
弗蘭茲長呀長呀，只有到了聖誕節的時候，又變小了
My father said, Franz becomes small, so that he freezes less.
我父親說，弗蘭茲變小了才不會被凍著
And I believed him. Until I understood that every I ate Franz every christmas.
然後我相信他了，直到我明白每個聖誕節吃的就是弗蘭茲
The story is made up right?
這故事是你編的吧？
Does she knows who you are?
她知道你是誰嗎？
I know who you are.
我知道你是誰
The game is called: Who am I.
這遊戲叫做：我是誰
The game sucks.
爛遊戲
You don't need to play along.
你可以不參加
I want to be Lady Gaga.
我想當Lady Gaga
The game is different.
這遊戲是另外玩法
The person to your left decides who you are and he or she writes it on a piece of paper
坐在你左邊的那個人可以決定你是誰 那個人將寫一張紙條
and then stick it onto your forehead.
然後貼在你的額頭
I am sorry but I can't do that.
抱歉，我辦不到
Everyone will play along.
大家都要玩
Please stay here.
請留下
You can only ask questions that can be answered with yes or no.
你可以提問，然後對方只能用「是」或「不是」來回答
CUNT
[屄]
His, I don't get it.
我看不明白他那張
Sorry, but...
抱歉，不過…
You start, you have to ask who you are!
你先來，你來問大家你是誰
Am I evil?
我是壞蛋嗎？
Good question.
好問題
Someone did evil to you but you also performed evil by yourself, yes you are evil.
有人對你做了不好的事情，而你也做了糟糕的 沒錯，你是壞蛋
Am I sexy.
我性感嗎？
It's not your turn until he gets a no.
直到才猜錯了以後，才能輪到你
Have I killed Nicolas.
我有殺了尼庫拉斯嗎？
Do you want some more juice?
還要喝點果汁嗎？
No, you haven't killed Nikolas.
沒，你沒有殺尼庫拉斯
Now it's Anjas turn.
現在輪到安雅了
Mrs. Heine it's your turn.
海納女士，該你了
Am I female?
我是女的？
For sure.
絕對的
That's insane.
簡直胡鬧
"There was an old spinster 0f street. Who bellowed, My cunt is on fire!"
「一個老女人來到了街上 高聲大叫，我的屄著火了」
So a fireman was found, brought his engine around, and extinguished her burning desire.
「消防員帶著工具趕來，拯救了慾火如焚的她」
Where is my son?
我兒子在哪裏？
Nicolas was so scared, he peed himself. He screamed mummy, mummy
尼庫拉斯嚇得尿了一褲子 他一直在哭喊：媽媽，媽媽
but he never said anything about daddy.
但他從沒提到過爸爸
Stay, please!
請留在這兒！
Do you want to know who you are?
你想不想知道你是誰？
I thought it's my turn?
現在應該輪到我了吧？
I give you a hint.
我給你個提示
I want to ask something, too!
我也想要玩
Your parents wanted to tell you, when you are old enough to understand.
你的父母本想等你長大了之後再告訴你的
But then you found your adoption certificate.
可你發現了自己的領養證
By accident or did you search for it.
偶然的…還是你特意尋找的
Did you sense that they are not your real parents?
你是不是感覺到他們不是你親生父母？
Am I sexy?
我性感嗎？
You are an anonymous birth. Your biological parents are unknown.
你出生就是無名氏，你的生父母下落不明
This game sucks.
什麼狗屎遊戲
How does it fell
你的感覺如何？
when you don't know who you are, and where you come from?
當你突然不知道自己是誰，從哪裏來
When our own mother doesn't want you?
為什麼自己的親生母親會把你拋棄？
Then he felt very bashful, and tucked his head under his wing.
然後他開始難為情起來，把自己的頭深埋到翅膀之下
He did not know what this was all about.
他自己不明白是為什麼
He felt so very happy, but he wasn't at all proud, for a good heart never grows proud.
他覺得很高興，但不覺得驕傲 好心腸的人是不應該驕傲的
He thought about how he had been persecuted and scorned,
他想到了自己過去是如何被欺負被嘲笑
and now he heard them all call him the most beautiful of all beautiful birds.
而現在卻聽到大家都稱讚他是所有美麗的鳥兒中最美的
The lilacs dipped their clusters into the stream before him,
紫丁香在他面前也都彎腰把枝條伸到了水中
and the sun shone so warm and so heartening.
陽光是如此的溫暖，如此的柔和
He rustled his feathers and held his slender neck high,
他撲扇了自己的翅膀，伸直了細長的脖子
as he cried out with full heart:
從內心發出響亮的叫聲：
"I never dreamed there could be so much happiness, when I was the ugly duckling."
「當我還是一隻醜小鴨的時候 我做夢也沒想到現在是如此幸福」
Beautiful ending.
結局真美
You forgot the good night kiss.
你忘記晚安吻了
The boy was handed in by an unknown person in the baby flap of the children's hospital Albert Sabin.
這孩子是被人匿名送交給阿爾伯特·薩賓兒童醫院的
The Infant was hypothermic and regarding the umbilical cord at least 24 hours old.
嬰兒當時體溫過低，從臍帶判斷，已經出生24小時
He was treated medically and at the end of an eight, week period given up for adoption.
醫療救治了八周之後，他被允許接受收養
The infant was 24 hours old, that means his birthday is tomorrow not the day after
既然這樣，那就是說，他的生日不是後天，而是明天
With Foundlings, the handover date is classified as the official date of birth.
對於棄嬰，往往會把他的接管日作為官方的出生日期
The real date is known solely by the mother
或許只有他的生母才知道其真實生日
Who gave the child his name?
誰給孩子起的名？
The adoptive parents.
養父母
Until then the infant remained nameless. In the provisional certificate of birth,
在那個時候，嬰兒還沒有任何名字 在他的臨時出生證上
is an X instead of the name.
姓名一欄填的是一個「X」
I didn't know you are a bastard.
我不知道你竟然是個私生子
Promise, that you never stand me up again, like the funfair Will you promise me that?
向我保證，你再也不會像在遊樂園那樣放我鴿子了 能發誓嗎？
Are you Gay?
你是同性戀？
Don't you like me?
不喜歡我？
Your tits are too small.
你連乳房都沒有！
Asshole.
混蛋
Is it possible to find out, who the mother of the child is?
能想辦法找出來誰是這孩子的母親嗎？
With baby flaps, no chance, everything is anonymous.
從接收棄嬰的過程來看，沒有任何信息 一切都是匿名的
But six months late; a young women appears in the
不過這裏寫了：六周之後，一個年輕女子出現在…
youth welfare office and claims to be the mother of the child.
…青年福利局聲稱她是孩子的母親
She wanted her child back,
然後想要回孩子
but the adoption was already completed.
可領養程序已經完成了，所以沒成功
Did she try to contact her child?
她有嘗試聯繫孩子嗎？
She did, but the adoptive parents refused it. Her name was included in the documents,
有，但養父母拒絕了 檔案裏應該有她的名字
nothing else could be done for hen Her maiden name was Anja Wehling.
我也只能幫到你這裏了 那女人的名字叫安雅·威林
Today she is called Heine.
現在改姓海納
Hello Claudia, are you still there?
喂，克勞迪婭，你在聽嗎？
He did an internship in the youth wellfare office.
他在青年福利局做的社會實習
Leave me alone！
走開！
You and your wife, how did you get to know one other
您跟您的愛人是怎麼認識的？
At the university cafeteria , she didn't like her meal, I gave her mine.
在大學的餐廳，她不喜歡吃她的那份，我就把自己的給了她
You did not know anything about this?
您也對此毫不知情？
Five days ago, we were just a normal family.
五天之前，我們還只是一個正常的家庭
Why didn't tell me about this!
為什麼不告訴這件事？
You lied to me! 12 years!
你竟然騙了我十二年！
I'm your husband! It's all about OUR child.
我是你丈夫！而這事關係到我們的孩子！
There's no sense...talk to me now!
沒必要這樣了…現在跟我談談！
What do you want?
你要幹嘛？
I want to sleep in bed with mummy.
我想要跟我媽一起睡
Shit.
見鬼
I can't sleep.
我睡不著
Nobody has ever read to me.
沒人試著來理解我
I heard about your father My father died when I was al little kid, too.
我聽說了你父親的事，我父親也在我很小的時候去世的
You can save your psycho stuff. I don't know where the victim is.
你少跟我用心理療法了 我不知道那個受害者在什麼地方
Morning.
早
You look totally gay.
你看上去真基佬
And you have no clue how to do it properly.
而且…你根本不知道該怎麼弄
One line here.
這兒劃一條
But not too strong, your lashes are already quite dark.
不過不能太濃，你的睫毛已經很濃了
And now this.
還有這個
What's going on here?
這兒怎麼回事？
I don't know.
我不知道
Surprise!
驚喜喲！
How nice that you were born, we would have really missed you otherwise.
你的降臨是多麼美妙，我們是如此地期待
"How nice that we're all together; we congratulate you, birthday child!"
我們在一起是最美好的事，祝賀你，小壽星
Happy Birthday.
生日快樂
Aren't you happy?
不高興嗎？
My birthday is tomorrow, not today.
我生日是明天，不是今天
Tomorrow?
明天？
Your birthday is today.
你是今天生日
Tomorrow.
明天
No, today.
不，今天
You have to blow out the candles.
你現在得吹蠟燭了
I am afraid I don't have a present for you, cause I only just heard about it.
可惜我沒能給你準備禮物，我總是最後才知道
But I have a present for you.
不過我有禮物給你
Here you are. Your name is written on the present.
禮物上有寫你的名字
I don't have a name.
我沒有名字
I gave it to you, when you were born.
你出生的時候，我給你取了名的
Tell me where Nicolas is, then I tell you your name.
告訴我尼庫拉斯在哪，我就告訴你的名字
Tell me, where Nicolas is? Then I will give you your name.
告訴我,尼庫拉斯在哪裏？ 然後我就把你的名字給你
He is in the cellar of the water park.
他在水上樂園的地下室
Marienbad, where we were yesterday?
瑪麗亞水世界，我們昨天去的那個？
Where is your telephone? Your telephone!
你們的電話呢？你們的電話！
Happy Birthday, Leon.
生日快樂，萊昂
I want you to go now. Leave my house and never come back!
我希望你現在就走，離開我的屋子，再也不要回來！
I thought, we would celebrate together
我以為我們要一起歡慶的
You are arrested provisionally.
你被暫時拘押了
What? You can't do that, we are kids.
什麼？你們不能這樣的，我們還是孩子
As of today no longer
從今天起不再是了
Come on!
快點兒！
You promised that we celebrate his birthday today, all together
你保證過今天我們要一起歡慶生日的，大家一起！
You promised it!
你保證過的！
No, you promised it.
不行，你保證過的
But you promised it.
不要，你發過誓的
A promise is a promise!
保證過了就要做到！
Don't you want to say Good Bye at least?
你至少應該跟我告別一下吧？
Bye.
拜拜
A Real Good Bye!
要正兒八經的！
Hands Up!
舉起手來！
Into the cellar you pussies!
到地下室去，臭女人！
Where is my child?
我的孩子在哪兒？
They didn't find him.
他們沒找到他
WHERE IS MY CHILD?...WHERE IS MY CHILD? ...WHERE IS MY CHILD?
我的孩子在哪裏？…
You fucked it up.
你把事情搞砸了
There is no way back for him now.
現在找不回他了
He will not do it.
他不會那麼做的
Go and get a rest Mrs. Doctog we can handle this from here.
去睡一覺吧，博士！這裏交給我們來辦
You look tiered.
你看上去太累了
Crazy, you actually look quite similar. At least if you know it.
真神奇，你們倆個真的很像 至少，在知道真相後再比較
Look at the mouth, it looks just like yours.
瞧他的嘴巴，就跟你的一樣
Look the corners of the mouth!
瞧啊，嘴角這裏！
You just can't see it, because of the... the...
你不願意看，因為那叫什麼來著……
Mathilda, I am trying to concentrate here.
瑪蒂爾達，我現在需要集中注意
Sorry.
抱歉
You are scared like shit.
你害怕了
Of cause I am scared, do I look like a psycho, or what?
當然害怕啊！難道我是殺人狂嗎？
I can do it for you. The cops will fuck you.
我可以替你辦，警察會找你麻煩的
They will fuck me anyway.
他們反正會找我麻煩
Your mother loved his mouth more than yours.
跟你比起來，你媽媽更喜歡他的嘴巴
Although you have the same.
雖然你們倆的長一樣
We don't have the same mouth.
我們的嘴巴不一樣
Why not, you are brothers?
為什麼不一樣，你們是兄弟
Half brothers.
半個兄弟
Brothers, half brothers, fuck it! You have the same mouth.
兄弟，半個兄弟，管它的！反正你們的嘴巴長一樣
Mathilda, would you please wait outside?
瑪蒂爾達，你能去外面等著嗎？
Mathilda, would you please wait outside!
瑪蒂爾達，麻煩你去外面等著！
I bet, you don't dare it.
我打賭你不敢殺他！
Give it back!
還給我！
It's mine, I stole it!
槍是我的，是我偷來的！
But the victim is mine.
但他這人屬於我
Noisless: I'm sorry!
[對不起！]
Shit!
媽的！
The mother opens the flap from the outside and puts her baby here into the bed.
媽媽在屋外打開傳遞箱，把她的孩子放進這床上
The bed detects that there is a child and automatically warms up.
床馬上會探測到有孩子躺上來了，就會自動加溫
If the flap closes again, a silent alarm is set off and we take care of the baby.
等傳遞箱再次合上 無聲報警器就會啟動，我們就會過來照料孩子
Really quite simple.
其實就這樣簡單
Do some mothers leave something for their children, some kind of keepsake?
那些孩子的母親會給她們的孩子留下什麼東西嗎？ …紀念物之類
Whatever we find next to the child we keep in these envelopes.
不管我們在孩子身上發現什麼，都會放在一個信封裏保管
From the age of sixteen, the children have the right to inspect these things.
等孩子到了十六歲，就可以接管這些東西
May I see the boy's envelope ?
我能看一下這個孩子的信封嗎？
Do you know what's in there?
你知道裏面是什麼嗎？
Sometimes a bad past is better than none.
有時候，一段糟糕的過往也強過什麼都不留
Anna Heinzke, I baptise you in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit.
安娜·海因澤克，我以聖父，聖子以及聖靈的名義給予你洗禮
Amen.
阿門
The Lord bless you and keep you.
主會保佑你，伴隨你
The Lord lift his countenance upon you, and be gracious to you.
主會時刻支持你，給你仁慈
The Lord make his face to shine upon you and give you peace.
主會永遠善顏待你，給你安寧
Amen.
阿門
Come! You are going to get your birthday present.
來…來拿你的生日禮物
Today is you birthday, we have to celebrate that.
今天是你的生日，我們肯定要慶祝一下
As long as the pussys are singing this house is ours.
只要那些人的歌聲沒停，那這屋子就屬於我們
Relax!
放輕鬆！
I swear, there is booze somewhere.
我發誓在這兒能找出酒來
To you!
敬你！
Here drink! Drink!
給，喝吧！喝呀！
It will make you relax.
會讓你放鬆一點的
Drink!
喝吧！
This will be my birthday present.
這將是我給你的生日禮物
Do you like what you see?
喜歡你看到的嗎？
Do you like me?
喜歡我嗎？
Then show me!
那就讓我看到！
Show me that you like me!
讓我看到你喜歡我！
Happy Birthday, Leon.
生日快樂，萊昂
If I ask you for something, will you do it?
要是我讓你做什麼事，你會做嗎？
No matter what it is?
不管是什麼事？
Yes.
是的
Tomorrow at breakfast with mum and dad, we will bring it to an end.
明天跟爸媽一起吃早飯，我們把事情解決掉
Leon?
萊昂？
I will bring the buns.
我會帶麵包來
We have this more often, sometimes stones, vomit, deposit bottles...
經常會發生這樣的事，有時候會有空瓶子
you can forget that, the alarm has a delay of fifteen minutes,
這個你就不用想了，警報是推遲了十五分鐘的
so that the mother stays anonymous.
這樣的話，可以使那一方的人完全不被人發現
I am here.
我在這兒
Your father raped me I am sorry, Mum.
是你爸爸強姦了我，對不起！ --媽媽
Had a nice day?
- 祝你愉快！ - 你也是，再見
Morning. Awake so early?
早呀！這麼早就起了？
Yes.
恩
I would like to have four of these normal buns.
唔…我想要四個這種普通的麵包
Two custard tarts and... another two of these cross, stuff.
這邊的布丁派，要兩個 然後…那邊十字形的也是兩個
You will talk now, and we keep out of it.
你們現在要相互談一談，我們在外面呆著
What do you want?
你想要讓我怎麼做？
Tell me who I am.
告訴我，我是誰
Did you know him?
你認識他嗎？
I was drunk. I just wanted to forget all that. Three weeks laterl was pregnant.
我當時醉了，而且一心想忘記那事情 三周之後，發現自己懷孕了
Why didn't you abort me?
那為什麼不去墮胎？
I was still covered by my parents' health insurance.
我那時候的醫保還掛在父母的戶頭上
Bullshit.
胡扯
I was ashamed.
我羞愧萬分
I thought it was all my fault I shouldn't have drank so much.
我覺得都是自己的錯，不該喝那麼多的
And then?
然後呢？
What then? I got you.
什麼然後？我就把你生了
Where?
哪裏？
On the toilet.
廁所裏
Alone on the toilet.
我一個人在廁所裏
You were screaming all the time. I did not know what to do?
你一直在哭，我不知道該怎麼辦
When the flap closed, I felt so relieved, ...like all this never happened.
當那個蓋板合上之後，我覺得自己解脫了 …好像這一切從未發生過
Did you give Nicolas the breast?
你有給尼庫拉斯餵過奶嗎？
Did you suckle him?
有沒有給他餵奶？
Yes.
有
Me too?
我也是？
No.
沒
If you amputate someone's leg, he can still feel it tickling, even years late:
要是你割斷某人的腿，他還會感覺到癢，甚至幾年後還會
When Nicolas is dead, where will it tickle you?
要是尼庫拉斯死了，你會覺得哪裏癢？
You didn't do it.
你沒殺他
I know Nicolas is well.
我知道尼庫拉斯沒事
You want to see him? It's no pretty sight.
你想看他？那可不是什麼好景致
Let me alone.
別煩我！
I hate you.
我恨你
I am sorry.
對不起
I am so sorry.
真的對不起
Hello? We will now eat breakfast all together
你好？ 我們現在要一起吃早飯
Like a real family?
像真正的一家子
Hello? ...Hello?
喂？…有人嗎？
I brought buns?
我帶了麵包來
Would you hand me the jam, please?
能把果醬拿給我嗎？
Strawberry, please.
草莓味的
Thank you.
謝謝
Oh, the coffee is ready.
喔，咖啡煮好了
Milk?
要牛奶？
The weather is so beautiful today.
今天的天氣真是不錯呀
Shall we go for a walk?
要不要一起走走？
But you promised it.
怎麼？你們說好了的
A promise is a promise.
保證過了就要做到！
You promised it. You can't do that.
你們保證了，但卻不去做
You always fool me. You always promise something but you never keep it.
你們總是耍我，你們總是保證做一件事，卻從不實現
A PROMISE IS A PROMISE!
保證過了就要做到！
Asshole!
混蛋！
Mum! Dad!
媽！爸！
Say, that you love me!
說你愛我！
Say it!
快說！
Leon?
萊昂？
Leon, I...I would like to see you...
萊昂，我…我想要…
I forgot Mathilda.
我忘記瑪蒂爾達了
Me too.
我也是
Claudia...
克勞迪婭
are you all right?
你沒事吧？
I have tried to reach you all the time.
我一直試著想聯繫你呢
I have to tell you something.
我有事要告訴你
Just come in for now.
先進來吧